Alma Gluck Scrapbooks and Other Materials
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Alma Gluck Scrapbooks and Other Materials 1902-1940 (bulk 1909-1918)
ML31.G48
Gluck, Alma, 1884-1938
approximately 200 items 10 containers 5.0 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Alma Gluck was a Romanian-born American soprano and voice teacher. This collection principally consists of scrapbooks related to her professional career. It also includes photographs, annotated sheet music, correspondence, clippings, and other assorted materials.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Gluck, Alma, 1884-1938--Archives.; Gluck, Alma, 1884-1938--Correspondence.; Gluck, Alma, 1884-1938--Photographs.; Gluck, Alma, 1884-1938.; Gluck, Alma, 1884-1938.; Sembrich, Marcella, 1858-1935.; Zimbalist, Efrem.
Subjects
Operas--Excerpts--Vocal scores with piano.; Sopranos (Singers)--United States.
Form/Genre
Clippings (Information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographic prints.; Scrapbooks.
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift, Marcia Davenport, March 1973.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Transfers
Sound recordings have been transferred to the Library of Congress Motion Picture, Broadcasting, and Recorded Sound Division.
Related Material
The Library of Congress Music Division holds several collections that contain correspondence from Alma Gluck, the most notable being the Elizabeth Sprague Coolidge Collection. Additional correspondence is present in the Damrosch-Blaine,
Damrosch-Tee Van
, Schwerke, and A.P. Schmidt collections.
Access and Restrictions
The Alma Gluck Scrapbooks and Other Materials are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time. Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1884 May 11 Born Reba Fiersohn in Romania
1886 Father Israel Fiersohn dies
1890 Moves to New York with mother Anna Fiersohn
1902 Marries insurance agent Bernard Gluck
1903 Daughter Abigail (Marcia Davenport) born
1906-1909 Studies voice with Arturo Buzzi-Peccia
1909 November 16 Debut performance with Metropolitan Opera Company as Sophie in Werther
1909 November 28 Debut performance at Metropolitan Opera House stage
1910 October 18 First song recital at Mendelssohn Hall
1912 Divorces Bernard Gluck
1912-1913 Studies voice with Marcella Sembrich
1913 Begins recording for Victor Records
1913 June 15 First song recital in London
1914 July 15 Marries violinist Efrem Zimbalist
1916 summer Daughter Marie Virginia born
1916 August 6 Mother Anna Fiersohn dies
1919 Son Efrem Zimbalist Jr. born
1925 May 25 Last recital at Manhattan Opera House
1938 October 27 Dies from cirrhosis of the liver at the Rockefeller Institute, New York
Scope and Content Note
The Alma Gluck Scrapbooks and Other Materials span the period 1902-1940, with the majority of the materials dating from 1909-1917. Gluck's distinguished career as an operatic singer is chronicled in eleven scrapbooks filled with clippings of performance reviews and other musical activities, including recording releases with Victor Records and voice studies with Marcella Sembrich. Interspersed are articles pertaining to personal matters such as her divorce from Bernard Gluck, marriage to Efrem Zimbalist, and other subjects.
The "Photographs" series consists of fifty-nine black and white images of family portraits, concert tours, and assorted publicity shots. Included are photographs of Efrem Zimbalist with Walter Damrosch and an album from Gluck's World War I performances at Camp Lewis, Washington. The "Music" series is comprised almost entirely of annotated and unannotated printed piano-vocal scores, the exception being a tunebook with melodic lines scrawled in the singer's hand. The remaining materials include several letters, articles, obituaries and sympathy cards, and reviews of Marcia Davenport's biography on Mozart.
Organization of the Alma Gluck Scrapbooks and Other Materials
This Alma Gluck Scrapbooks and Other Materials are organized in 4 series:
Scrapbooks, 1909-1917
Photographs, 1902-1928
Music, 1900s-1920s
Miscellany, 1913-1940
http://lccn.loc.gov/2010561029
Container List
- Scrapbooks, 1909-1917 (Box 1-7)
  - 1909 November 16 - 1910 September 8, [30] p. (Box 1)
  - 1910 September 9 - 1911 October 20, [30] p. (Box 2)
  - 1911 October 4 - 1912 January 29, [72] p. (Box 3)
  - 1912 January 31 - 1912 June 9, [36] p. (Box 3)
  - 1912 March 21 - 1912 December 8, [71] p. (Box 3)
  - 1913 January 22 - 1914 July 31, [91] p. (Box 4)
  - 1913 June 10 - 1914 March 28, [98] p. (Box 4)
  - 1915 April 24 - 1916 June 30, [149] p. (Box 4)
  - 1914 July 10 - 1915 January 17, [149] p. (Box 5)
  - 1916 July 28 - 1916 December 6, [149] p. (Box 6)
  - 1916 November 25 - 1917 April 4, [100] p. (Box 7)
- Photographs, 1902-1928 (Box 8)
  - 1902, 1907-1913, 12 black and white photographs (Box-folder 8/1)
  - 1909-1913, 18 black and white photographs; Principally AG in various opera roles (Box-folder 8/2-3)
  - 1917-1918, 20 black and white photographs; Includes: New York Symphony tour; World War I performances at Camp Lewis (Box-folder 8/4)
  - 1919, 1928, 9 black and white photographs (Box-folder 8/5)
- Music, 1900s-1920s (Box 8-9)
  - Beethoven, Ludwig van
    - Adelaide, AG annotations (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Loin de ma tombe obscure (Box-folder 8/6)
  - Brahms, Johannes
    - Dort in den Weiden (Box-folder 8/7)
    - O liebliche Wagen (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Vorschneller Schwur, AG annotations (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Haydn, Joseph
    - La vie (Box-folder 8/8)
  - Lehmann, Liza
    - In a Persian garden, Autograph printed score; Inscribed by AG to Arturo Toscanini (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Lully, Jean Baptiste
    - Amadis. Bois apais redouble ton ombre, AG annotations (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Martini, Jean Paul Egide
    - Plaisir d'amour, AG annotations (Box-folder 8/10)
  - Méhul, Etienne Nicolas
    - Joseph. Air de Joseph (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Monsigny, Pierre-Alexandre
    - O ma tendre musette (Box-folder 8/11)
  - Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus
    - Alleluia, AG annotations (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Cosi fan tutte, Incomplete (Box-folder 9/2)
    - Idomeneo. Zeffiretti lusinghieri, AG annotations (Box-folder 9/3)
    - Lieder, AG annotations; Edition Peters plate number: 6703 (Box-folder 9/4)
    - Lieder, AG annotations; Edition Peters plate number: 9536-9537 (Box-folder 9/5)
  - My favorite songs: Alma Gluck (Box-folder 9/6)
  - Rosa, Salvator
    - Only smile, I will ask nothing more (Box-folder 9/7)
  - Schubert, Franz
    - Die Forelle (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Heidenröslein (Box-folder 9/8)
    - Der Lindenbaum (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Die Post, Incomplete (Box-folder 9/9)
    - An Sylvia, AG annotations (Box-folder 9/9)
  - Schumann, Robert
    - Auftrage (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Er ist's, AG annotations (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Frühlingsnacht, AG annotations (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Intermezzo (Box-folder 9/11)
    - Der Nussbaum, AG annotations (Box-folder 9/11)
  - Strauss, Richard
    - Du meines Herzens Krönelein (Box-folder 9/12)
  - Tunebook, AG holograph manuscript notebook with melodic lines and texts; [63] p. (Box-folder 9/13)
- Miscellany, 1913-1940 (Box 10)
  - Alma Gluck Zimbalist Memorial performance, 1940 November 23, Programs and clippings (Box-folder 10/1)
  - Articles about AG, 1913, 1938-1939, undated (Box-folder 10/2)
  - Letter from AG to Marcia Davenport, undated, Holograph manuscript, in ink; [1] p. (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Letter from [Uncle] Dan Froham to AG, April 15, Holograph manuscript, in ink; [1] p.; AG response attached (Box-folder 10/3)
  - Marcia Davenport materials, 1932, undated, Articles and reviews related to her biography on Mozart (Box-folder 10/4)
  - Obituaries, 1939, undated (Box-folder 10/5)
  - Sympathy notes and cards regarding death of AG, Notable correspondents: Carl Engel; Geraldine Farrar; Sinclair Lewis; Lily Pons; John D. Rockefeller Jr.; Elizabeth Shumann; Arturo and Carla Toscanini; Alice Damrosch Wolfe; Bruno Zirato (Box-folder 10/6)
  - Davenport, Marcia. Mozart. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons, 1932, Printed edition inscribed to AG (Box 10)